<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UAV Mapping Guidelines</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UAV Mapping Guidelines</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/pages/00-acknowlegements-abbreviations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/00-acknowlegements-abbreviations/</guid>
      <description>Technical Guidelines for Small Island Mapping with UAVs © 2019 International Bank for Reconstruction and Development / International Development Association or The World Bank
1818 H Street NW, Washington DC, 20433 www.worldbank.org
This work is a product of independent consultants working in collaboration with The World Bank and Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team. Part of the funding that supported this work was provided by the Australian Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade (DFAT) through the Pacific Humanitarian Challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Objective of This Guidance Note</title>
      <link>/pages/01-objective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/01-objective/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this guidance note is to establish key principles for end use of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) in a Pacific Island Country (PIC) context. The document addresses how, when, and for what applications UAVs should be used. For pilots who are new to UAV mapping, it also provides instructions and recommendations to ensure that imagery of high quality is generated for accurate integration with other geospatial layers.
The ultimate goal is to establish UAVs as the principal data collection and survey mapping instrument for Small Island Developing States in the Pacific region and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. UAVs as a Game Changer for PICs</title>
      <link>/pages/02-uavs-as-a-game-changer-for-pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/02-uavs-as-a-game-changer-for-pics/</guid>
      <description>The Pacific region is one of the most disaster-prone regions of the world. It is subject to a variety of natural hazards, including floods, tropical cyclones, earthquakes, tsunamis, droughts, and volcanic eruptions. Geospatial data can play a key role in monitoring hazard conditions on the ground, but unique data collection challenges exist for PICs. Because these counties consist of multiple small islands or atolls that are often very remote from one another, it difficult to collect geospatial data at the appropriate scale for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Securing UAV Flight</title>
      <link>/pages/03-securing-uav-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/03-securing-uav-flight/</guid>
      <description>Securing UAV Flight Authorization and Permits in the Pacific Flying UAVs requires a thorough understanding of local and national civil aviation regulations. Many governments now provide specific provisions for UAV operations, including permits and licenses that must be obtained before even entering the country. To learn about countries’ specific requirements and rules for flying UAVs, the Global Drone Regulations Database is a good starting point.1
New Zealand regulations are the most prevalent in the Pacific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Determining Whether the UAV is the Right Mapping Tool</title>
      <link>/pages/04-determining-whether-the-uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/04-determining-whether-the-uav/</guid>
      <description>UAVs may not always be the best mapping tool for a project. Before deciding whether to use a UAV, a satellite, or other tool, the project’s data needs, budget, and time frame must be understood. Table 2 lists some key factors to consider when deciding on the tool to use.
Table 8. Comparison of Survey Mapping_ _Methods
    Satellite  Airplane  UAV    Approximate area covered in a day  10,000 km2  750 km2  10–25 km2 (for a UAV equivalent to an eBee)a    Detail level  30–50 cm/pixel   6–30 cm/pixel  3–10 cm/pixel    Cost per 10 km2  $$  $$$  $    Cost per 1 million km2  $  $$  $$$$    Time to deploy  24 hours–1 week  3 days  24 hours (provided flight permits have been granted)    Ease of deployment  Easy (once the satellite is in orbit)  Medium  Easy    Blocked by clouds  Yes  Depends on altitude  No (though may be blocked by fog and rain)    Blocked by wind  No  Yes  Yes    Regulatory burden  Low  Medium–high  High    Note: The number of $ denote relative costs: least costly ($) to most costly ($$$$)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Choosing the Right UAV Platform</title>
      <link>/pages/05-choosing-the-right-uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/05-choosing-the-right-uav/</guid>
      <description>If a UAV is the right tool, the next decision concerns which platform to use. There are multiple factors to consider in making this choice: the purpose of the data capture, the weight of platform allowed by local regulations under the conditions of the intended survey location, the need for weatherproofing, and the project’s technical requirements (e.g., the type of sensor/camera needed for the survey).
The choice of platform has a number of consequences:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Choosing the Sensor</title>
      <link>/pages/06-choosing-the-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/06-choosing-the-sensor/</guid>
      <description>Many survey mapping UAV platforms come with built-in or recommended cameras, which are already configured for optimal mapping outcomes. However, built-in cameras may also limit the user’s ability to customize optimal sensor configurations.
Preferred camera specifications The UAV’s flight altitude and sensor determine the spatial resolution of the imagery. To put this another way, the focal length, sensor size (size of the chip that detects light), and density of detectors on that chip all influence the altitude required to collect data of a given spatial resolution (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7. Preparing for the UAV Mission</title>
      <link>/pages/07-preparing-for-the-uav-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/07-preparing-for-the-uav-mission/</guid>
      <description>Time management The actual flying of UAVs is the least time-consuming part of the process. Figure 5 shows the relative proportion of time needed for each step of the entire UAV mapping process, starting from preparation and including flying and post-processing. If the UAV mission will fly under circumstances that require special approvals, it can take anywhere from a few weeks to a few months to obtain these approvals; in addition, the approvals may be expensive, especially in cases where approval to fly higher than 400 ft is being sought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8. Managing Work Flow in the Field</title>
      <link>/pages/08-managing-work-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/08-managing-work-flow/</guid>
      <description>UAVs are often small enough to be carried in backpacks, but usually a motor vehicle such as a small pickup truck is used to carry the associated equipment, including the survey equipment (base station) if GCPs are being used. A vehicle also provides shelter in case of inclement weather, and the vehicle battery or cigarette lighter plug can be used to recharge UAV batteries and laptops in the field during long survey missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9. After the Flight: Processing the Data</title>
      <link>/pages/09-after-the-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/09-after-the-flight/</guid>
      <description>Flying and collecting imagery is often the easiest step in UAV mapping, while preparing and processing imagery often requires significant computing and human efforts. Photogrammetric software that employs processes such as Structure from Motion (SfM) is actively and continuously improved to reduce the level of effort required and to automate the processing work flow.
Processing software and hardware Most software used to process UAV data is developed by commercial firms and offered through pricey subscription options or permanent desktop licenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Handling Project Management</title>
      <link>/pages/10-handling-project-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/10-handling-project-management/</guid>
      <description>Managing a UAV project requires attention to a number of concerns:
 Lithium batteries. Lithium polymer (LiPo) batteries used in UAVs are highly flammable and must be transported in LiPo safety bags when traveling. On commercial flights, passengers are allowed a maximum of two 100–160 Wh batteries, which must be kept in carry-on luggage.1 Quantities of smaller batteries are not usually limited, but some airlines or airport security staff may take away what they perceive as excessive quantities of batteries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11. Case Study</title>
      <link>/pages/11-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/11-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Post–Tropical Cyclone Gita Mission in Tonga On February 12, 2018, Tropical Cyclone Gita hit the island nation of Tonga as a Category 4 hurricane, causing major damage across Tongatapu, the main island, as well as the neighboring island of Eua. The total economic loss was estimated at approximately 38 percent of gross domestic product, triggering international support for long-term recovery. At the request of Tonga’s National Emergency Management Office, the UAV4Resilience (UAV4R) team deployed to Tonga to capture post-disaster UAV aerial images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12. Conclusions</title>
      <link>/pages/12-conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/12-conclusions/</guid>
      <description>12. Conclusions The agility and versatility of UAVs as data collection platforms stand to significantly improve the availability of timely spatial data to small island countries. UAV technology should be harnessed to further improve resilience, risk reduction, and disaster response work in small island contexts. To ensure that this work can go forward, adequate capacity building, training, and preparation are needed. This Guidance Note has discussed the most important factors to take into account in using UAVs and UAV technology effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annex 1</title>
      <link>/pages/annex-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/annex-1/</guid>
      <description>Annex 1. Applying for Approvals in Fiji and Tonga for October 2017 UAV Field Testing Fiji
CAA Fiji outlined the following path to obtaining necessary approvals for UAV operation:
 Submit completed Form OP138 to CAA, accompanied by the following documents:
 Proposed pilots’ remote pilot licenses Letter of intent from the sponsoring organization, such as the World Bank UAV operations manual Third-party liability insurance cover letter  Obtain permission from the operator of the airspace—i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>